Hello.
My name is Zephyr Clarke-Dolberg from Miami Dog Training.
In this clip we're going to teach you how to walk a dog.
Now number one is with the leash.
Sometimes, you know, people get confident, over confident with their dogs off leash and, you know, something spooks a dog, it sees a cat, it runs out into the street and that can cause problems.
So walking a dog number one should be done on the leash.
Preferably a five to six foot leash.
I prefer a five foot leash.
And a leather leash, you know, your tools are, are your biggest asset when you're working with your dog or walking with your dog.
So, walking with your dog, you always want to make sure that you are the leader you're in the front.
So I'm going to ex, ex, show you an example of that right now.
You notice she stays behind me.
She's not advancing forward because she needs to read my body language to see what she should do next.
She should be always looking for a cue from you.
So, and as you can see when I stop she sits and she's relaxed.
So, when you're walking your dog you always want to stay controlled.
And always walk them on one side so they're not confused about going back and forth.
This is Zephyr Clarke-Dolberg and this has been how to walk a dog.